<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Example on RIDDL Documentation</title><link>https://riddl.tech/tutorial/rbbq/</link><description>Recent content in Example on RIDDL Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>reid@reactific.com (Reid Spencer)</managingEditor><webMaster>reid@reactific.com (Reid Spencer)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 14:38:08 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://riddl.tech/tutorial/rbbq/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>RBBQ Scenarios</title><link>https://riddl.tech/tutorial/rbbq/scenario/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>reid@reactific.com (Reid Spencer)</author><guid>https://riddl.tech/tutorial/rbbq/scenario/</guid><description>Case Study The Reactive BBQ restaurant chain has determined that their existing restaurant operations system is not suitably meeting their needs and have hired a high technology consulting company to provide some needed guidance on how they can improve their customer service, tracking, and reliability.
What follows are the interviews conducted with key personnel at Reactive BBQ in order to identify the issues.
CEO of Reactive BBQ How would you describe your restaurants?</description></item><item><title>Reactive BBQ</title><link>https://riddl.tech/tutorial/rbbq/reactivebbq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>reid@reactific.com (Reid Spencer)</author><guid>https://riddl.tech/tutorial/rbbq/reactivebbq/</guid><description>Render https://github.com/reactific/riddl-examples/blob/main/src/riddl/ReactiveBBQ/ReactiveBBQ.riddl Everything in RIDDL revolves around creating domains and subdomains. These are logical groupings of definitions that belong together, presumably because they mimic and organizations structure or some other logical, real world groupings. Domains can be nested.
At this top level of definition we can see that a single domain named ReactiveBBQ represents the entire enterprise. The details of that top level domain is abstracted away via three include statements within its body, one for each of the subdomains:</description></item></channel></rss>