<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Reactive BBQ Case Study on RIDDL Documentation</title><link>https://riddl.tech/tutorial/rbbq/scenario/</link><description>Recent content in Reactive BBQ Case Study on RIDDL Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>reid@reactific.com (Reid Spencer)</managingEditor><webMaster>reid@reactific.com (Reid Spencer)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 14:38:08 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://riddl.tech/tutorial/rbbq/scenario/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CEO of Reactive BBQ</title><link>https://riddl.tech/tutorial/rbbq/scenario/ceo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 14:36:43 -0700</pubDate><author>reid@reactific.com (Reid Spencer)</author><guid>https://riddl.tech/tutorial/rbbq/scenario/ceo/</guid><description>How would you describe your restaurants?
Reactive BBQ is a family restaurant with 500 locations across 20 countries. We&amp;rsquo;re open for breakfast, lunch and supper. Our specialty at Reactive BBQ is our award winning Reactive Ribs, but we are also well known for our tender steaks and our slow roasted chicken. We take traditional BBQ flavours and give them a bit of a spicy punch. The customer experience at each Reactive BBQ should have the same high level of quality across the globe.</description></item><item><title>Corporate Head Chef</title><link>https://riddl.tech/tutorial/rbbq/scenario/headchef/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 14:36:52 -0700</pubDate><author>reid@reactific.com (Reid Spencer)</author><guid>https://riddl.tech/tutorial/rbbq/scenario/headchef/</guid><description>What is your role in the restaurant?
Corporate wants each restaurant to have a consistent experience. My job is to create new recipes to be included in the menu. I spend a lot of time trying out different ingredients and flavours to try to get the right balance for our menu. I have to be careful to stick to ingredients that we can buy in sufficient quantities. Most people think that a restaurant like ours prepares everything from scratch.</description></item><item><title>Host</title><link>https://riddl.tech/tutorial/rbbq/scenario/host/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 14:37:00 -0700</pubDate><author>reid@reactific.com (Reid Spencer)</author><guid>https://riddl.tech/tutorial/rbbq/scenario/host/</guid><description>What is your role in the restaurant?
I answer phones and record reservations. I also greet and seat guests as they arrive at the restaurant. Guests can either call, or use the website to make reservations, so it is necessary for me to consult the system before I seat customers. I also need to update the reservations system when I seat customers so that someone online can&amp;rsquo;t reserve the same table.</description></item><item><title>Server</title><link>https://riddl.tech/tutorial/rbbq/scenario/server/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 14:37:06 -0700</pubDate><author>reid@reactific.com (Reid Spencer)</author><guid>https://riddl.tech/tutorial/rbbq/scenario/server/</guid><description>What is your role in the restaurant?
I greet guests at their table, help them understand the menu and make recommendations, then take their food and drink orders. After taking their order I input it into our computer system. When the order is ready I pick it up from the kitchen or bar and deliver it to the table.
When the guest is finished, I present the bill and settle at the table.</description></item><item><title>Bartender</title><link>https://riddl.tech/tutorial/rbbq/scenario/bartender/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 14:37:14 -0700</pubDate><author>reid@reactific.com (Reid Spencer)</author><guid>https://riddl.tech/tutorial/rbbq/scenario/bartender/</guid><description>What is your role in the restaurant?
I take drink orders at the bar and entertain the guests. I mix the drinks and take them to the customers when they are ready. When the customer is done for the day I help them settle their tab.
I also mix drink orders for the servers in the restaurant. The servers deliver those drinks. I just get them ready and leave them on a tray with the table number so the servers know where they go.</description></item><item><title>Chef</title><link>https://riddl.tech/tutorial/rbbq/scenario/chef/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 14:37:29 -0700</pubDate><author>reid@reactific.com (Reid Spencer)</author><guid>https://riddl.tech/tutorial/rbbq/scenario/chef/</guid><description>What is your role in the restaurant?
I oversee the entire kitchen and all of its staff. I source local ingredients required to prepare our menu items. The menu is decided on monthly and distributed via email. I inspect all prepared orders that leave the kitchen.
What challenges do you face?
I think the worst thing is when the system that prints our orders goes haywire. Sometimes the system crashes and orders get lost.</description></item><item><title>Cook</title><link>https://riddl.tech/tutorial/rbbq/scenario/cook/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 14:37:33 -0700</pubDate><author>reid@reactific.com (Reid Spencer)</author><guid>https://riddl.tech/tutorial/rbbq/scenario/cook/</guid><description>What is your role in the restaurant?
Depending on the day, I work at different stations in the kitchen. The chef tells me where I will be working for that day. I prepare orders according to the tickets that get printed out at my station. Once an order is ready, I take it over to a station where we gather all the pieces of that order. The chef then approves it and we notifiy the server that their order is ready.</description></item><item><title>Delivery Driver</title><link>https://riddl.tech/tutorial/rbbq/scenario/deliverydriver/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 14:37:41 -0700</pubDate><author>reid@reactific.com (Reid Spencer)</author><guid>https://riddl.tech/tutorial/rbbq/scenario/deliverydriver/</guid><description>What is your role in the restaurant?
I deliver for five locations around the city. We don&amp;rsquo;t get a lot of deliveries. We aren&amp;rsquo;t a pizza place after all. but our wings and ribs are popular delivery options. I am on call for each of the delivery locations. If one of them gets a delivery, I get a notification on my phone. I go pick up the food from the location nearest the customer.</description></item><item><title>Online Customer</title><link>https://riddl.tech/tutorial/rbbq/scenario/onlinecustomer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 14:37:49 -0700</pubDate><author>reid@reactific.com (Reid Spencer)</author><guid>https://riddl.tech/tutorial/rbbq/scenario/onlinecustomer/</guid><description>Describe how you place an order online with Reactive BBQ
Well, I go to the website and they have their menu there. I have a look at the menu and decide what I want. The menu is organized into different sections, like lunch, dinner, appetizers, dessert, that sort of thing. The menu online isn&amp;rsquo;t identical to what I get in the restaurant, but it&amp;rsquo;s pretty close. I have also done it through the phone app they have.</description></item></channel></rss>