<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Introduction on RIDDL Documentation</title><link>https://riddl.tech/introduction/</link><description>Recent content in Introduction on RIDDL Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>reid@reactific.com (Reid Spencer)</managingEditor><webMaster>reid@reactific.com (Reid Spencer)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 15:08:30 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://riddl.tech/introduction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What Is RIDDL?</title><link>https://riddl.tech/introduction/what-is-riddl/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 10:07:32 -0700</pubDate><author>reid@reactific.com (Reid Spencer)</author><guid>https://riddl.tech/introduction/what-is-riddl/</guid><description>RIDDL gets its name from an acronym that stands for Reactive Interface with Domain Definition Language.
RIDDL is a specification language for the niche of large, distributed, reactive, concurrent systems such as required for modern internet-scale applications or corporate back office infrastructure.
RIDDL is a variety of software libraries and tools, provided in this GitHub repository, that allow humans to work with the language to create their own derivative works.</description></item><item><title>What can RIDDL do?</title><link>https://riddl.tech/introduction/what-can-riddl-do/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 10:07:32 -0700</pubDate><author>reid@reactific.com (Reid Spencer)</author><guid>https://riddl.tech/introduction/what-can-riddl-do/</guid><description>RIDDL is a software specification language. As a consequence of it being a language, it has a software tool, riddlc (riddl compiler), that can be used to do a variety of things. Most of those things involve reading riddl input files, checking them, and producing some output file(s).
Input The input to riddlc is always a single file with the .riddl suffix. This is a text file that contains definitions in the RIDDL syntax.</description></item><item><title>What is RIDDL Based On?</title><link>https://riddl.tech/introduction/what-is-riddl-based-on/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 14:15:51 -0700</pubDate><author>reid@reactific.com (Reid Spencer)</author><guid>https://riddl.tech/introduction/what-is-riddl-based-on/</guid><description>The RIDDL specification language borrows concepts from:
Domain Driven Design (DDD) Reactive System Architecture (RSA) C4 Model Of Software Architecture Akka Agile User Stories Behavior Driven Development (BDD) Finite State Machines Command/Query Separation CQRS Event Sourcing Saga Pattern Unified Modeling Language (UML) RIDDL aims to capture business concepts, system designs and architectural details in a way that is consumable by business professionals yet can also be directly translated into various technical and non-technical artifacts, including:</description></item><item><title>Who Can Benefit From RIDDL?</title><link>https://riddl.tech/introduction/who-can-benefit-from-riddl/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 10:07:32 -0700</pubDate><author>reid@reactific.com (Reid Spencer)</author><guid>https://riddl.tech/introduction/who-can-benefit-from-riddl/</guid><description>RIDDL is technology-agnostic, but not design-agnostics. It is purposefully aimed at the design of large scale, distributed systems based on reactive architecture. It allows specification of the design of a system, without regard to programming language, cloud vendor choice, or specific technology choices. Using RIDDL allows a living design to evolve through every stage of the development process and then through continuing maintenance and evolution of the system designed.
Consequently, the people who can benefit from RIDDL are those who are building such systems that want a precise and consistent way of specifying its evolving design as a guide to all stakeholders.</description></item><item><title>Who Made RIDDL Possible?</title><link>https://riddl.tech/introduction/who-made-riddl-possible/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 10:07:32 -0700</pubDate><author>reid@reactific.com (Reid Spencer)</author><guid>https://riddl.tech/introduction/who-made-riddl-possible/</guid><description>Originator Reid Spencer Deeply experienced system architect, software developer and entrepreneur. Initiated RIDDL in 2019 and started committing changes to the repository at the end of 2021 Founder of Reactific Software LLC which was bought by Ossum Inc. in 2022 which he also founded. Contributors James Lovell The original enthusiast, co-conspirator, shaper and user of the language, etc. RIDDL wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be where it is today without James&amp;rsquo; contributions.
Kevin D&amp;rsquo;Vincenzo An early implementor of a hugo translator that inspired much of the current implementation.</description></item><item><title>How Can I Get Help?</title><link>https://riddl.tech/introduction/how-can-i-get-help/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>reid@reactific.com (Reid Spencer)</author><guid>https://riddl.tech/introduction/how-can-i-get-help/</guid><description>Here are some options for getting help. Pick the item below that best fits your needs:
I Need A Bug Fixed I Need RIDDL To Generate Something Else I Want To Make A Feature Suggestion I Need Commercial Support I Just Want To Chat With Someone About RIDDL I Need A Bug Fixed While RIDDL is competent enough to be used for a production software project, we still consider it to be in a pre-release, early preview stage.</description></item></channel></rss>