<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Common on RIDDL Documentation</title><link>https://riddl.tech/language/common/</link><description>Recent content in Common on RIDDL Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>reid@reactific.com (Reid Spencer)</managingEditor><webMaster>reid@reactific.com (Reid Spencer)</webMaster><atom:link href="https://riddl.tech/language/common/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Descriptions</title><link>https://riddl.tech/language/common/descriptions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>reid@reactific.com (Reid Spencer)</author><guid>https://riddl.tech/language/common/descriptions/</guid><description>The RIDDL syntax is simply a hierarchical arrangement of definitions. Each definition can have a description. Descriptions are used to generate documentation and follow markdown conventions.
Examples There are several ways to describe a definition. In each of the examples we attach a description to some domain named Foo. The definition is not important for our purposes here. Descriptions come after the definition using one of four phrases:</description></item><item><title>Examples</title><link>https://riddl.tech/language/common/examples/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>reid@reactific.com (Reid Spencer)</author><guid>https://riddl.tech/language/common/examples/</guid><description>RIDDL uses Gherkin examples in various places to express a functionality or behavior requirement on the definition that uses it. Gherkin examples are used in these places:
Adaptors Entity Handlers Functions Processors Saga Actions Story Structure Gherkin is a language developed by SmartBear Software, a vendor of software quality tools, for the cucumber testing system. RIDDL uses a subset of the language as SmartBear has defined it.</description></item><item><title>Types</title><link>https://riddl.tech/language/common/types/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>reid@reactific.com (Reid Spencer)</author><guid>https://riddl.tech/language/common/types/</guid><description>Introduction The RIDDL language allows users to define data types. Definitions of types are more limited in RIDDL than in programming languages on purpose. The type system must be easily understandable by non-programmers as the domain engineer or domain expert is likely the most frequent user.
Predefined Types RIDDL supports several predefined types that just &amp;ldquo;exist&amp;rdquo; because they are fundamental and well understood in any targeted computing environment.</description></item><item><title>Expressions</title><link>https://riddl.tech/language/common/expressions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>reid@reactific.com (Reid Spencer)</author><guid>https://riddl.tech/language/common/expressions/</guid><description>RIDDL allows expressions to be specified in various places. Most frequently they are the operands to message constructors and when clauses in Gherkin examples. This page shows you what you can do with expressions in RIDDL.
Expressions Expressions compute values of arbitrary types. Since RIDDL is not a programming language, the syntax used for expressions is minimal and abstract. There is no attempt in RIDDL to be computationally complete.</description></item><item><title>Includes</title><link>https://riddl.tech/language/common/includes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>reid@reactific.com (Reid Spencer)</author><guid>https://riddl.tech/language/common/includes/</guid><description>An include statement is not a RIDDL definition but an instruction to the compiler to lexically replace the include statement with the content of another file. The name of the file to include is the statement&amp;rsquo;s only parameter, like this:
include &amp;#34;other-file.riddl&amp;#34; The include statement is only permitted where major definitions are expected, specifically at root level, and in the bodies of domain, context, entity, and pipe definitions.</description></item><item><title>Functions</title><link>https://riddl.tech/language/common/functions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>reid@reactific.com (Reid Spencer)</author><guid>https://riddl.tech/language/common/functions/</guid><description>Introduction Functions are pieces of processing that can be attached to entity, consumer, and api definitions. A function has a set of inputs (its requirements) and a set of output (what it yields). Functions need not be pure and often have side effects through the state changes of an entity.
Example Here&amp;rsquo;s an example of a function, named riddle, that requires a Subject(String) type and returns a Riddle (String) type.</description></item><item><title>Interactions</title><link>https://riddl.tech/language/common/interactions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>reid@reactific.com (Reid Spencer)</author><guid>https://riddl.tech/language/common/interactions/</guid><description>Introduction An Interaction evolves from the concepts inherent in a UML Sequence Diagram. Instead of specifying those concepts in a visual way, as in UML, RIDDL specifies them in a textual way. The purpose of an interaction is to specify an important way in which the system components communicate and cooperate to accomplish a task that is valuable to the stakeholders of the system.
As with the UML concept, an interaction shows the message flow between system entities in time sequence.</description></item><item><title>Imports</title><link>https://riddl.tech/language/common/imports/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>reid@reactific.com (Reid Spencer)</author><guid>https://riddl.tech/language/common/imports/</guid><description>This feature is not implemented yet.
An import statement may be used to import a definition from a BAST file that was generated from a prior compilation. Import statements help to save time when a prior compilation has completed and been saved as a BAST file.</description></item></channel></rss>