<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Context on RIDDL Documentation</title><link>https://riddl.tech/language/root/domain/context/</link><description>Recent content in Context on RIDDL Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>reid@reactific.com (Reid Spencer)</managingEditor><webMaster>reid@reactific.com (Reid Spencer)</webMaster><atom:link href="https://riddl.tech/language/root/domain/context/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Features</title><link>https://riddl.tech/language/root/domain/context/features/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>reid@reactific.com (Reid Spencer)</author><guid>https://riddl.tech/language/root/domain/context/features/</guid><description>A Feature is a requirement on a context. Features are specified very similarly to the Gherkin language. The same keywords are used and the style is more like RIDDL syntax. If you&amp;rsquo;re already familiar with Gherkin then an example should suffice:
Feature &amp;#34;Guess the word&amp;#34; is { // The first example has two steps Scenario &amp;#34;Maker starts a game&amp;#34; is { When the Maker starts a game Then the Maker waits for a Breaker to join } // The second example has three steps Scenario &amp;#34;Breaker joins a game&amp;#34; is { Given the Maker has started a game with a word When the Breaker joins the Maker&amp;#39;s game Then the Breaker must guess a word knowing the length of the Maker&amp;#39;s word choice.</description></item><item><title>Context Handler</title><link>https://riddl.tech/language/root/domain/context/handler/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>reid@reactific.com (Reid Spencer)</author><guid>https://riddl.tech/language/root/domain/context/handler/</guid><description>This page is stale and no longer accurately reflects context handlers. Please refer to the handler concept for further clarity. ß A handler definition in a context specifies how that bounded context should handle messages sent to it.
Note that an Entity can define a handler too, but they are different than the handlers defined in a context. See Entity Handler for more details. There are two kinds of handlers as described in the following sections.</description></item></channel></rss>